- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪
- Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!!
- 呼呼！
是的！！
- Meow.
- Oh, Gary, I'm so excited!
- 喵。
- 哦，加里，我太兴奋了！
Tonight they're showing
the only episode
今晚他们将展示
唯一的一集
of "Mermaidman and Barnacleboy"
that I've never seen!
《美人鱼与藤壶男孩》
我从来没有见过！
Whoo-hoo!
- Meow, meow!
呼呼！
- 喵，喵！
♪ ♪
- It was lost...
- 丢了...
to the sands of time.
到时间的沙子。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[shouting]
[喊叫]
Until they found a copy in the
producer's underwear drawer.
直到他们在
生产商的内衣抽屉。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
- Meow.
- 喵。
- It's part two of
the two-part special,
- 这是第二部分
两部分特别版，
"The Case of
the Curious Cliff Hanger."
“案例
好奇的悬崖吊架。”
Well, I've rearranged
the living room
嗯，我已经重新安排了
客厅
for optimal TV viewing.
- Meow?
以获得最佳的电视观看效果。
- 喵？
- The popcorn's a-popping.
- Meow.
- 爆米花爆开了。
- 喵。
- And the soda's on ice.
- 苏打水是冰镇的。
All that's left is to set
the VCR to record
剩下的就是设置
要录制的 VCR
so I can relive the magic
over and over forever.
这样我就可以重温魔法
一遍又一遍，直到永远。
Hmm, but which tape to use?
Don't have any blank ones left.
嗯，但是该使用哪种磁带呢？
不要留下任何空白。
Hmm.
Oh, here we go.
唔。
哦，我们开始吧。
Who needs a tap of their
own birth, anyway?
谁需要点击他们的
无论如何，自己出生？
Yoop, done!
哟哟，完成了！
Now it's just one quick shift
at the Krusty Krab,
现在只是一个快速转变
在蟹堡王店，
and I'll be back for
the evening's entertainment.
我会回来的
晚上的娱乐活动。
[laughs]
[笑]
♪ ♪
Normally I like working,
平时我喜欢工作，
but today is moving so slowly.
但今天进展得很慢。
♪ ♪
both: [chewing]
两者：[咀嚼]
♪ ♪
- [chewing]
- [咀嚼]
♪ ♪
- Oh, at this rate
I'm never gonna see
- 哦，按照这个速度
我永远不会看到
"Mermaidman and Barnacleboy."
“美人鱼和藤壶男孩。”
[groans]
[呻吟]
Hmm?
唔？
We'll help you get through
the day, SpongeBob.
我们会帮助您渡过难关
那天，海绵宝宝。
And tonight we'll conquer evil!
今晚我们将战胜邪恶！
Aww, you guys always
make me feel better.
哇，你们总是
让我感觉好点。
Hmm?
唔？
[laughs]
[笑]
narrator: One shift later..
旁白：一班之后..
- All right, bye, Squidward.
Bye, Mr. Krabs.
- 好吧，再见，章鱼哥。
再见，蟹老板。
See you tomorrow!
明天见！
- Oh, SpongeBob.
My boat has a flat tire.
- 哦，海绵宝宝。
我的船轮胎漏气了。
Could you help me change it?
你能帮我改一下吗？
- Oh, uh, well, I gotta
get home for "Mermaidman,"
- 哦，呃，好吧，我得
回家看《美人鱼》
but--but sure,
I guess I have a little time.
但是——但是可以肯定的是，
我想我还有一点时间。
- Oh, good.
Let me know when you're done.
- 哦，很好。
完成后请告诉我。
- Luckily I brought
all my tools.
-幸好我带了
我所有的工具。
Jack, wrench, hammer,
jackhammer--
千斤顶、扳手、锤子、
手提钻——
Whoa!
哇！
Jack-wrench, wrench-hammer,
hammer-hammer.
千斤顶扳手、扳手锤、
锤子锤子。
Okay, I'm ready.
好的，我准备好了。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
Gotta get that old tire off.
And...
得把那个旧轮胎拆掉。
和...
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[laughs]
[笑]
Yes? No.
Maybe if I try...
是的？不。
也许如果我尝试...
[groans]
[呻吟]
♪ ♪
Hmm.
A-ha.
唔。
啊哈。
- Ooh, ooh.
- Okay, Mrs. Puff.
- 哦，哦。
- 好的，帕芙女士。
Good to go.
很好，可以走了。
[engine revving]
[发动机转速]
[tires squealing]
[轮胎吱吱声]
- Thanks again, SpongeBob.
- 再次感谢，海绵宝宝。
- Oh, no problem, Mrs. Puff.
- 哦，没问题，帕芙女士。
[screaming]
[尖叫]
Hmm.
唔。
I still have time to get
home before my show,
我还有时间去获取
演出前回家，
if I pick up the pace.
如果我加快步伐。
[shouting]
[喊叫]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Ah, home sweet pineapple.
啊，家乡的甜菠萝。
- Hey, buddy.
You got a minute?
- 嘿，伙计。
你有时间吗？
- Oh, uh, not really, but--
- I double-parked my rock.
- 哦，呃，不是真的，但是--
- 我把我的石头并排停放了。
And it got towed.
它被拖走了。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
Could you help me get it back?
- Oh, uh, sure.
你能帮我把它拿回来吗？
- 哦，呃，当然。
Uh, but let's make it quick.
"Mermaidman" is on soon.
呃，但我们得快点。
《美人鱼》即将上映。
- You'se guys can take
a look around on your owns.
- 你们可以接受
自己环顾四周。
- They all look the same,
Patrick.
- 他们看起来都一样，
帕特里克.
How are we gonna
find your rock?
我们要怎样
找到你的石头了吗？
- Don't worry, buddy.
I'll know it when I feel it.
-别担心，伙计。
当我感觉到的时候我就会知道。
Oh, this might be it!
Give me a hand!
哦，可能就是这个！
帮我一下！
- [spits]
- [吐口水]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- No, this isn't it.
- 不，不是这个。
Oh, ooh,
this one might be it.
哦，哦，
可能就是这个。
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[sighs]
- [shouts]
[叹气]
- [喊叫]
No, this isn't it, either.
不，这也不是。
Ow! No.
噢！不。
[shouts]
No.
[喊叫]
不。
[screams]
No.
[尖叫声]
不。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[sighs]
[叹气]
- This is it.
This is my rock!
- 就是这样。
这是我的石头！
- Congratulations.
- 恭喜。
Now there's the little
matter of the fee.
现在有小
费用的问题。
- Oh, talk to him.
- [groans]
- 哦，和他谈谈。
- [呻吟]
Here you go.
干得好。
♪ ♪
[groans]
- Thanks, SpongeBob!
[呻吟]
- 谢谢，海绵宝宝！
See you at home
for "Mermaidman!"
在家见
为了“美人鱼！”
Whoo-hoo!
- Wait, wait, Patrick!
呼呼！
- 等等，等等，帕特里克！
Could you give me a...
ride?
你能给我一个...
骑？
[groans]
[呻吟]
♪ ♪
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- SpongeBob!
Oh, thank goodness you're here.
- 海绵宝宝！
哦，谢天谢地你在这里。
I could really use your help.
- Oh, hey, Sandy.
我真的需要你的帮助。
- 哦，嘿，桑迪。
Uh, I'm kind of in a rush
'cause "Mermaidman" is on
呃，我有点着急
因为《美人鱼》正在上映
and it's the lost episode--
这是丢失的一集——
- Oh, it won't take
more than a minute.
- 哦，这不会需要
超过一分钟。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- My laser acorn experiment
blasted a nut-sized hole
- 我的激光橡子实验
炸出了一个坚果大小的洞
in my dome.
在我的圆顶里。
Could you stick your finger
here while I go get
你能伸出你的手指吗
我去的时候在这里
my fix-it-up kit?
我的修理工具包？
- I don't really have
a lot of time to--
-我真的没有
很多时间去——
- Thanks, be right back!
- 谢谢，马上回来！
- Gosh, I can't wait to see
that long lost "Mermaidman"
- 天哪，我等不及要看了
那个失传已久的“美人鱼”
episode tonight.
- Oh, for sure.
今晚的剧集。
- 哦，当然。
No real fan would miss it.
Not for the world.
没有真正的粉丝会错过它。
不为世界。
- Yeah.
- [laughs]
- 是的。
- [笑]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- All righty, SpongeBob.
I'm ready to--What?
- 好吧，海绵宝宝。
我准备好——什么？
♪ ♪
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
That's it!
No more distractions!
就是这样！
没有更多的干扰！
I am gonna--
[groans]
我要——
[呻吟]
- Boy-o, you gotta help me
sort me loose change.
- 男孩，你得帮我
帮我整理零钱。
- But "Mermaidman."
- 但是“美人鱼”。
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Heh.
Thanks, boy-o.
- 呵呵。
谢谢，男孩。
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Don't wanna miss it!
不想错过！
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Heh.
- But "Mermaidman."
- 呵呵。
- 但是“美人鱼”。
But "Mermaidman."
但《美人鱼》。
♪ ♪
But "Mermaidman."
但《美人鱼》。
[whistling]
[吹口哨]
But "Mermaidman."
但《美人鱼》。
♪ ♪
[sighs]
[叹气]
Well, I may have missed
the live broadcast,
嗯，我可能错过了
现场直播，
but at least I got
it all on tape.
但至少我得到了
一切都在磁带上。
Here I come, "Mermaidman."
我来了，“美人鱼”。
Oh.
Where'd I put my keys?
哦。
我把钥匙放哪儿了？
♪ ♪
Did I leave them
on the table again?
我离开他们了吗
又上桌了？
No, my tape!
不，我的磁带！
My soda!
我的苏打水！
My popcorn!
My "Mermaidman!"
我的爆米花！
我的“美人鱼”！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
Meow.
喵。
- [crying]
- Meow.
- [哭泣]
- 喵。
♪ ♪
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[crying]
[哭泣]
- Hey there, SpongeBob.
Why all the waterworks?
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
为什么都是自来水厂？
- [sniffling]
- [抽鼻子]
I was so busy helping
everyone that I missed
我正忙着帮忙
我想念的每个人
"Mermaidman and Barnacleboy"
and my VCR didn't record it
《美人鱼与藤壶男孩》
我的录像机没有录制它
and now I'll never see it
and my life has no meaning.
现在我再也看不到它了
我的生活没有任何意义。
[crying]
[哭泣]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
- All right, listen up.
- 好吧，听着。
SpongeBob has helped
every single one of us
海绵宝宝帮忙了
我们每一个人
dozens of times over.
几十次以上。
But we ain't been very
helpful to him today.
但我们并没有很
今天对他有帮助。
- Yeah, I was a lousy friend.
- 是的，我是一个糟糕的朋友。
- Now, we may have taken
advantage of his kindness,
- 现在，我们可能已经采取了
凭借他的善良，
but I got a plan
to make things right.
但我有一个计划
使事情正确。
[whispering]
[耳语]
narrator: The next day.
旁白：第二天。
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
♪ ♪
Play.
玩。
[swallowing]
[吞咽]
[chewing]
[咀嚼]
[knocking]
[敲门声]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Hey there, SpongeBob.
Feeling any better?
- 嘿，海绵宝宝。
感觉好些了吗？
- [muttering]
- [嘀咕]
- Aww, why don't you
come with me?
- 哇哦，你为什么不呢？
跟我来吗？
I have a little
surprise for you.
我有一点
给你惊喜。
- I'm not really in the mood,
Sandy.
-我实在没心情
桑迪。
- Aww, quit acting like
a calf with colic.
- 哇哦，别再表现得像
患有肠绞痛的小牛。
- [groans]
- Come on, SpongeBob.
- [呻吟]
- 来吧，海绵宝宝。
♪ ♪
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Gee, Sandy, where'd you get
an outdoor amphitheater?
哎呀，桑迪，你从哪里来的？
室外露天剧场？
- Don't worry about that.
- 别担心这个。
Just sit right here
and enjoy the play.
就坐在这里
并享受比赛。
- Oh, okay.
- 哦好的。
[piano music]
[钢琴音乐]
- [groans]
[microphone squeals]
- [呻吟]
[麦克风尖叫声]
[humming]
Welcome, ladies and morons!
[嗡嗡声]
欢迎，女士们和白痴们！
It's time for the exciting
conclusion to...
激动人心的时刻到了
结论是……
"The Case of the Curious
Cliffhanger!"
《好奇者的案例》
悬崖勒马！”
[laughs]
[笑]
- Huh?
Whoa!
- 啊？
哇！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Help me, Barnacleboy.
I'm hanging...
- 帮帮我，藤壶男孩。
我挂了...
from this cliff.
从这个悬崖。
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- And look, I am also
hanging from this cliff.
- 看吧，我也是
悬挂在这个悬崖上。
We sure are in danger.
我们确实处于危险之中。
- [shudders]
- [颤抖]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
You should give up
while you can, Mermaidman.
你应该放弃
both: [grunting]
两人：[咕哝]
♪ ♪
[shouts]
[喊叫]
- Haven't you heard,
Captain Tightwad?
- 你没听说过吗
船长太紧了？
I'll never give up fighting...
Um...
我永远不会放弃战斗...
嗯...
Line?
- Oh, um...
线？
- 哦，嗯...
Evil.
- Evil!
邪恶的。
- 邪恶的！
- Hmm?
[groans]
- 唔？
[呻吟]
- [shouts]
- [喊叫]
- Wow!
- 哇！
Yes, yes!
是的，是的！
all: ♪ He may be half
a mermaid ♪
所有人：♪ 他可能是一半
一条美人鱼♪
♪ And he may be half a man ♪
♪ 他可能是半个男人 ♪
♪ But to us he's more
than a hero ♪
♪ 但对我们来说他更重要
比英雄♪
♪ He's our Mermaidman ♪
♪ 他是我们的美人鱼 ♪
- [moaning]
- [呻吟]
[whistles]
[口哨声]
Ah, oh, bravo!
Bravo!
啊，哦，太棒了！
太棒了！
Bravo!
[laughing]
太棒了！
[笑]
Yes!
Ah!
是的！
啊!
Thank you, everyone.
I loved the show.
谢谢大家。
我喜欢这个节目。
And I loved the love
you showed me.
我爱过这份爱
你给我看了。
And I loved how you showed me
the love you showed me
我喜欢你向我展示的方式
你向我展示的爱
in the show I love.
在我喜欢的节目中。
This is my favorite episode
of "Mermaidman" ever.
这是我最喜欢的一集
曾经的“美人鱼”。
all: [cheering]
全体：[欢呼]
- Ahem.
Hey!
- 咳咳。
嘿！
What are you kids doing
in my outdoor amphitheater?
你们孩子在做什么
在我的露天剧场？
- [screams]
Cheese it, everyone!
- [尖叫]
大家来干酪吧！
It's Old Man Jenkins!
[screams]
这是老詹金斯！
[尖叫声]
- Come back!
- 回来吧！
I just wanna be in the play.
我只是想参加戏。
- Aww, I'll play with you,
Old Man Jenkins.
- 哇哦，我会和你一起玩，
老詹金斯。
Do you wanna be Mermaidman?
你想成为美人鱼吗？
- It's the role of my dreams.
- 这是我梦想的角色。
Zoom!
飞涨！
[laughs]
[笑]
Whoo!
呼！
- [laughs]
- [笑]
[spooky music]
[诡异的音乐]
♪ ♪
- Oh, it was so great
catching up with you Hannah.
- 哦，太棒了
追上你汉娜。
- Oh.
- It's been too long.
- 哦。
- 已经太久了。
- [sneezes]
- [打喷嚏]
- Oh, you poor thing.
Sounds like you have a bug.
-哦，你这个可怜的东西。
听起来你有一个错误。
Better go home and reboot.
最好回家重新启动。
Remember, only keywords
tonight.
记住，只有关键词
今晚。
You need to rest
your processor.
你需要休息
你的处理器。
- Karen!
- 凯伦！
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
- What do you want?
[sneezes]
- 你想要什么？
[打喷嚏]
[groans]
[呻吟]
- Oh, no.
Your nodes are swollen.
- 哦，不。
你的节点肿胀。
That old bucket of bolts
gave you a computer virus.
那桶旧螺栓
给你带来了计算机病毒。
- Oh, nonsense.
I'm the fastest computer alive.
-哦，废话。
我是世界上最快的计算机。
[stammering]
[结巴]
♪ ♪
[crashes]
[崩溃]
Uh-oh.
[laughs]
呃哦。
[笑]
My ones and zeroes look like
10, 10, 10, 10.
我的 1 和 0 看起来像
10、10、10、10。
- Someone's gonna have to get
inside you and kill that virus.
- 总得有人得到
在你体内并杀死该病毒。
It's probably
a suicide mission.
大概是
自杀任务。
But who would be stupid
enough to--
但谁会傻呢
足以——
[knocking]
- [grunting]
[敲门声]
- [咕哝]
- What now?
- [groans]
- 现在怎么办？
- [呻吟]
- Oh, I'm just helping out
the Health Department.
-哦，我只是帮忙
卫生部门。
- Hmm?
"Sanitary notice.
- 唔？
“卫生通知。
"The Chum Bucket hereby
gets a grade Z
“特此密友桶
获得 Z 级
from the Health Department."
来自卫生部门。”
Hey, that's up from
a negative Z last week.
嘿嘿，这是从
上周Z为负值。
- Congratulations, Plankton.
- 恭喜你，浮游生物。
In a few more years,
you're sure to get an F.
再过几年，
你肯定会得到F。
[groans]
Whoa!
[呻吟]
哇！
- Never mind about that.
I have a snow job--
- 别介意这个。
我有一份雪地工作——
Uh, job for you.
Karen needs your help.
呃，工作给你。
凯伦需要你的帮助。
She asked for you personally.
她亲自来找你。
- ♪ Who lives in the crabapple
under a pea ♪
- ♪ 谁住在海棠里
在豌豆下面♪
- Hey, catchy song.
- 嘿，好听的歌。
♪ ♪
- ♪ Observant and yellow
fellow is he ♪
- ♪ 敏锐且黄色
同胞就是他♪
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- We need a name
for this mission.
- 我们需要一个名字
为了这个使命。
How about, "Journey to
the Center of Karen"?
怎么样，“旅程
凯伦中心”？
No.
"The Mainframe Mission."
不。
“大型机任务。”
Nah.
Ooh, I know.
不。
哦，我知道。
"Operation: Save Karen."
“行动：拯救凯伦。”
[baby giggling]
[宝宝咯咯笑]
- Whatever, just blast
the virus when you see it.
- 无论如何，只是爆炸
当你看到病毒时。
- Oh, like this?
- Hmm?
- 哦，像这样吗？
- 唔？
[lasers screeching]
[激光刺耳]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
Oops.
- That tickles.
哎呀。
- 好痒啊
[laughs]
[笑]
- [blows]
- [打击]
Here, use this.
在这里，用这个。
- But Plankton,
how am I supposed to--
- 但是浮游生物，
我该怎么做——
Whoa!
哇！
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
[laughing]
[笑]
Ow!
噢！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
♪ ♪
[grunts]
- [laughing]
[咕哝]
- [笑]
- [grunts]
Don't worry, baby.
- [咕哝]
别担心，宝贝。
Help is on the way.
- Get away.
帮助正在路上。
- 逃离。
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
Ow.
噢。
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
♪ ♪
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
Whoa.
哇哦。
♪ ♪
Super-awesome-ular-tastic!
Wow!
超级棒-好吃！
哇！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Huh?
- SpongeBob, can you hear me?
啊？
- 海绵宝宝，你能听到我说话吗？
Come in, SpongeBob.
[groans]
进来吧，海绵宝宝。
[呻吟]
Talk to me,
you digitized doofus!
跟我说话，
你这个数字化的傻瓜！
- Plankton, I do not
respond to insults.
- 浮游生物，我不
回应侮辱。
- [sighs]
Okay.
- [叹气]
好的。
Just look for any destruction
and follow it to the virus.
只是寻找任何破坏
并追踪病毒。
Sweetheart.
- Got it, honey.
亲爱的。
- 明白了，亲爱的。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Whoa!
[stammering]
哇！
[结巴]
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
I want a Krabby Patty.
[笑]
我想要一个蟹肉饼。
- Baby.
- Bye.
- 婴儿。
- 再见。
- [stammers]
- [结巴]
SpongeBob, hurry up
and kill that virus
海绵宝宝，快点
并杀死该病毒
before it completely
destroys Karen.
在它完全之前
摧毁了凯伦。
- [grunts]
[laughs]
- [咕哝]
[笑]
[glass shattering]
[玻璃破碎]
Knock, knock!
[grunts]
敲，敲！
[咕哝]
- Huh?
Great Neptune's nostrils!
- 啊？
伟大的海王星的鼻孔！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
- [groans]
[screams]
- [呻吟]
[尖叫声]
Huh?
Hmm.
啊？
唔。
[gasps]
The virus.
[喘气]
病毒。
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Whoa!
Huh?
哇！
啊？
Plankton, it looks like
the virus is heading
浮游生物，看起来像
病毒正在走向
to Karen's memory banks.
到凯伦的记忆库。
- Listen, if it gets
to her memory,
- 听着，如果有的话
在她的记忆中，
it'll fry her hard
drive completely.
它会把她烤得很硬
完全驾驶。
I need you to destroy
that virus right now!
我需要你摧毁
那个病毒现在！
- Plankton, I need you
to control your wife.
- 浮游生物，我需要你
来控制你的妻子。
Er, computer, or whatever.
呃，电脑，或者其他什么。
- Mind your own business,
Eugene.
- 管好自己的事，
尤金.
- This is my business!
- 这是我的事！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
Hello there, baby.
你好，宝贝。
Where've you been all my life?
我这辈子你都去哪儿了？
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
Please don't break up
our happy home.
请不要分手
我们幸福的家。
I forgive you, baby.
[kisses]
我原谅你，宝贝。
[亲吻]
Hmm.
唔。
♪ ♪
- Wow, I can never unsee that.
- 哇，我永远无法忽视这一点。
♪ ♪
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Hmm.
唔。
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- Intruder detected.
- 检测到入侵者。
[lasers charging]
[激光充电]
[lasers firing]
[激光发射]
[shouting]
[喊叫]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[explosions]
[爆炸]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[heroic music]
[英雄音乐]
♪ ♪
- Plankton?
- That's my name.
- 浮游生物？
- 那是我的名字。
Actually, I'm Karen's
version of Plankton.
其实我是凯伦的
浮游生物的版本。
You know, how she'd like
to see me.
你知道，她多么想要
来看我。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Ooh, you have beautiful eye.
- We'd better get moving.
- 哦，你的眼睛很漂亮。
- 我们最好动身了。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Ah.
[grunting]
- 啊。
[咕噜声]
[circus music]
[马戏音乐]
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- Anger control
center abolished.
- 愤怒控制
中心被废除。
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- Love center destroyed.
- 爱情中心被摧毁。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
♪ ♪
- [grunts]
- [chuckles]
- [咕哝]
- [轻笑]
- Money, money, money, money,
money, money, money, money...
- 钱，钱，钱，钱，
钱，钱，钱，钱……
- Mr. Krabs, is that you?
- 蟹老板，是你吗？
- It's Karen's
version of Krabs.
- 这是凯伦的
蟹蟹的版本。
- Hey, looking good,
Mr. K.
- 嘿，看起来不错，
K 先生
- I hate everything.
- 我讨厌一切。
- That's how Karen
sees Squidward.
- 凯伦就是这样
看到章鱼哥。
- Hmm?
- 唔？
Uh, nothing a little
makeup couldn't fix.
呃，没什么
化妆无法解决。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
Hey, I wonder if Karen has
a version of me down here.
嘿，我想知道凯伦有没有
这里是我的一个版本。
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
- Woop, woop, zing, zing.
Woop, woop, zing, zing.
- 呜呜，呜呜，叮叮，叮叮。
呜呜呜，叮叮叮。
- Ooh, now that guy's a hunk.
- 哦，现在那家伙是个大块头了。
[sirens blaring]
[警笛鸣响]
- Intruder in section B.
Eliminate.
- B 部分的入侵者。
消除。
all: [grunting]
全体：[咕哝]
[lasers firing]
[激光发射]
both: [grunting]
两人：[咕哝]
Hmm?
[lasers firing]
唔？
[激光发射]
- Ow!
- 噢！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- [laughs]
- Yeowch!
- [笑]
- 哟哟！
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Owie, owie, owie.
- 欧伊，欧伊，欧伊。
- What a drip.
- 真是滴水啊。
- Ai-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi!
- 哎呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀！
- [screams]
- Ai-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi-yi!
- [尖叫]
- 哎呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀呀！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
both: [grunting]
两人：[咕哝]
- Duh.
- 呃。
- Doy.
- 多伊。
- Duh.
- Dun.
- 呃。
- 邓。
- Doy.
- 多伊。
- Neptune's network!
- 海王星的网络！
Which one of you
is the real SpongeBob?
你们中的哪一个
是真正的海绵宝宝吗？
both: [muttering]
两人：[嘀咕]
- I'll have to use all
the computation power I have
- 我必须用尽一切
我拥有的计算能力
to figure this out.
Eeny, meeny, miney, moe.
弄清楚这一点。
Eeny，meeny，miney，moe。
[laser blasting]
[激光喷砂]
- Duh, duh, doy, doy.
Duh, duh, doy, doy.
- 呃，呃，多伊，多伊。
呃，呃，多伊，多伊。
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
I think I destroyed
the wrong SpongeBob.
我想我毁了
错误的海绵宝宝。
- Duh, duh, doy--
[groaning]
- 呃，呃，doy——
[呻吟]
How do I look?
- Stunning.
我看起来怎么样？
- 令人惊叹的。
Whoa!
哇！
- [grunts and shouts]
- [咕哝和喊叫]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Hmm.
唔。
Voracious virus!
贪婪的病毒！
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
There's still time
to save Karen.
还有时间
为了拯救凯伦。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
You first.
你先。
- [groans]
[mimics "Tarzan" scream]
- [呻吟]
[模仿“泰山”的尖叫声]
[groans]
Whoops.
[呻吟]
哎呀。
Did I do good?
我做得好吗？
- You did great.
- 你做得很好。
But I think you could use
a little push.
但我认为你可以使用
一点点推动。
- Whoa, okay, your turn.
- 哇，好吧，轮到你了。
- [groans]
It's up to you, SpongeBob.
- [呻吟]
这取决于你，海绵宝宝。
You must save Karen!
你必须救凯伦！
- No!
- 不！
- What do you mean, no?
- 你是什么意思，不？
- I mean,
yes!
- 我的意思是，
是的！
[beeping]
[嘟嘟声]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Uh, sweetie, maybe we should
slow down and pull over.
- 呃，亲爱的，也许我们应该
减速并靠边停车。
Honey?
Precious?
蜂蜜？
宝贵的？
- No way, Plankie!
It's me and you, amigo.
- 不可能，普兰基！
这是我和你，朋友。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Oh, hot dog.
Let's go dancing.
- 哦，热狗。
我们去跳舞吧。
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼！
Whoo-hoo, yeah!
Whoo-hoo!
呼呼，是啊！
呼呼！
- How are all these people
able to dance here
- 这些人都怎么样
能够在这里跳舞
in the middle of the day?
Don't they have jobs?
在中午？
他们没有工作吗？
- Whoo!
[laughs]
- 呼！
[笑]
- Ouch!
- 哎呀！
SpongeBob, come in, SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝，海绵宝宝，进来吧！
If you're gonna do anything,
do it now!
如果你想做点什么
现在就做吧！
Karen's about to melt down!
凯伦快要崩溃了！
- Oh, such a cute
one-eyed baby.
- 哦，真可爱
独眼宝宝。
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- [chomping]
- [咀嚼]
- Stop munching on those
memories, you monster!
- 别再咀嚼那些了
回忆，你这个怪物！
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
♪ ♪
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- Hi-ya!
- 嗨呀！
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
♪ ♪
- Meow?
- 喵？
[groans]
[呻吟]
♪ ♪
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Plankton, I'm at the edge
of Karen's memory.
浮游生物，我在边缘
凯伦的记忆。
She has to create
more memories.
她必须创造
更多回忆。
I need space to run.
我需要空间来奔跑。
- [shouting]
- [喊叫]
- Is my running after her
enough of a memory?
- 我在追她吗
内存够不够？
- Oh, I'm afraid not.
- 哦，恐怕不是。
[groans]
[呻吟]
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
♪ ♪
Roar!
吼！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
I always wind up
with one extra piece.
我总是会结束
多加一件。
- [snarls]
- [咆哮]
- Oh, you must be hungry.
- 哦，你一定饿了。
That's why you're eating
through Karen.
这就是你吃饭的原因
通过凯伦.
- I'm always hungry.
- 我总是很饿。
- You poor, ugly,
disgusting little virus.
- 你又穷又丑
恶心的小病毒。
I know what you need.
我知道你需要什么。
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- SpongeBob, I've decided
to pull you out.
- 海绵宝宝，我决定了
把你拉出来。
We're abandoning
Operation: Save Karen.
我们正在放弃
行动：拯救凯伦。
- I got the virus.
Look.
- 我感染了病毒。
看。
- Hmm?
- Hi, there.
- 唔？
- 你好呀。
- Here you go, little fella.
- 给你，小家伙。
It'll take the virus 300
years to chew its
病毒需要300
多年咀嚼它
way through this sandwich.
- Whoo-hoo!
穿过这个三明治。
- 呼呼！
- Oh.
Huh?
- 哦。
啊？
- Baby, you're all right.
- 宝贝，你没事吧。
- Nope, I'm still delirious.
- 不，我还是神志不清。
But I like it!
[laughs]
但我喜欢它！
[笑]
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
♪ ♪